BIZUAYEHU HUNDE

1281 Brockett Rd Apt # 4G, Clarkston, GA 30021 (678) 488-3243 b.andarssa@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self-motivated and resourceful professional with more than 20 years of extensive experience in project development and management, program administration, community empowerment, fundraising, consultancy and training services, and; proficient in the use of Microsoft Word, Excel and other software applications.

SKILLS

Proposal writing, communication and networking; Planning, training, fundraising, and supervision of staff;

Providing leadership and management direction; Designing and implementing a strategic plan.

WORK HISTORY

Produce Worker, 10/2018 to 01/2019

Your DeKalb Framers Market - Decatur, GA

- Assisted customers providing information on pricing, purchases and products; and
- Stocked, displayed, and rotated produce products.

Executive Director, 06/2015 to 07/2018

Organization for the Development of Women and Children-Ethiopia (ODWaCE) – Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Coordinated the administration, programs and strategic plan of the organization; and
- Served as a primary spokesperson and developed project proposals and raised funds from donors.

Network Coordinator, 02/2012 to 05/2015

Organization for the Development of Women and Children-Ethiopia (ODWaCE) – Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Organized activities such as meetings and workshops of the Female Genital Mutilation (FGM) Network members; and
- Maintained communication with FGM network partners.

Head of Program, 06/2010 to 09/2011

Women in Self Employment (WISE) - Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Provided ongoing oversight and management of program activities' implementation; and
- Conducted annual budget process and raised funds from donors.

Fundraising and External Relation Service Head, 11/2006 to 06/2010

Ethiopian Orthodox Church- Child and Family Affairs Organization(EOC-CFAO) - Addis Ababa-Ethiopia

Managed project proposals development, external communications, advocacy and resource mobilization requirements; **Project Coordinator**, 07/2005 to 06/2006

Ye Ethiopia Goji Limadawi Dirgitoch Aswegaj Mahiber, Ethiopia (EGLDAM) - Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Maintained plans, budgets and expenditures of UNICEF assisted project; and
- Kept projects on schedule by managing deadlines and adjusting workflow as needed.

Project Study And Design Expert, 03/2002 to 10/2002

Addis Ababa City Government, Foreign Relation And Economic Cooperation Bureau - Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Conducted supportive supervisions on charity organizations' projects and programs; and
- Appraised project proposals submitted by Charity organizations.

Counselor, 07/2001 to 03/2002

SOS Infants-Ethiopia – Addis Ababa, Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Identified orphan and vulnerable children who need special attention; and
- Provided individual counseling services to orphan and vulnerable children and followed up them to ensure the improvement of their situation.

Refugee Camp Coordinator, 03/1999 to 07/2000

Administration for Refugees and Returnees Affairs (ARRA) - Aisha, Somali Region, Ethiopia

- Supervised the administration and program activities of Aisha Refugee Camp;
- Ensured the preparation and maintenance of all financial records:

Social Worker, 02/1995 to 02/1999

Administration for Refugees and Returnees Affairs (ARRA) - Hart-Sheik, Somali Region, Ethiopia

- Assisted refugee communities solve and cope with problems in their lives; and
- Identified refugees who need help and linked them with essential services.

EDUCATION

Master of Arts: Social Anthropology, 2004 Addis Ababa University - Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

Bachelor of Arts: 1994

Addis Ababa University - Addis Ababa, Ethiopia